CHANDRA PRAKASH

Computer Scientist | Engineer | Architect | PMP

612-568-2426

cprakash@acm.org
https://github.com/chandra1123

SUMMARY

Chandra is an accomplished technologist. He is an IIT Delhi alumnus. Over past 25+ years, he has been researching and delivering software products and solutions across diverse domains.

Chandra has been in management positions for premier organizations such as Manhattan Associates, HSBC, GE, SAS and Wells Fargo.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science and Engineering Indian Institute of Technology, Delhi

CERTIFICATIONS

- 2018, Senior Member, ACM
- 2017, AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate
- 2016, TOGAF 9
- 2008, PMP
- 2008, SAS Certified Warehouse Architect
- 2007, SAS Certified Advanced Programmer for SAS 9
- 2006, Sun Certified Enterprise Architect

RECENT COURSES

- 2018, **Bitcoin and Cryptocurrency** Technologies from Princeton University via coursera.org
- 2015, **Machine Learning** from Stanford University via coursera.org
- 2015, **Data Science Specialization** from Johns Hopkins University via coursera.org
- 2014, **R Programming** from Johns Hopkins University via coursera.org
- 2014, Introduction to Interactive Programming in **Python** from Rice University via coursera.org
- 2014, Functional Programming Principles in **Scala** from École Polytechnique Fédérale de Lausanne via coursera.org
- 2013, Computational Investing from Georgia Institute of Technology via coursera.org

Phone: 612-568-2426 CHANDRA PRAKASH 1 of 2 Email: cprakash@acm.org

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

VICE PRESIDENT, KINETIX TRADING SOLUTIONS, Charlotte, NC, 2014 - TILL DATE

- Assisted a major bank set up Fort Mill development center.
- **Helped the bank pass CCAR** by building and supporting 4 complex finance and risk reporting systems in compressed time scales.
- Automated application monitoring and system maintenance activities for Market Risk by building a tool (Market Risk System Automation). This reduced human errors, generated time/cost savings and helped in compliance with organization policies.
- Developed Model Risk Management System which provides centralized repository of models, governance and control processes. This enabled the back to comply with federal regulations, improved risk management and reduced costs (by eliminating 5 legacy systems).

LEAD APPLICATION ENGINEER, WELLS FARGO, Charlotte, NC, 2010 - 2014

- Modernized Technology Stack of Enterprise Collections and Recovery platform (ECAR) from legacy PowerBuilder to Web based.
- Integrated ECAR with multiple systems by developing several inbound and outbound real-time interfaces using Queuing (WebSphere MQ and Oracle Advanced Queuing) and **Web Services** (Soap and REST).
- Developed multiple modules to **support government regulations** and business needs.

SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT MANAGER, SAS R&D, Pune, India, 2007 – 2010

- Developed "Search Interface to SAS Content" to surface SAS Content (e.g. reports, dashboards) from SAS Servers via **Enterprise Search** Facilities. **Managed the product development** from proof-of-concept stage to multiple end-user releases.
- Developed common user interface components Reusable Presentation Layer and Web-Tier UI components and frameworks which are consumed by SAS Products and Components.

TECHNICAL ARCHITECT, KANBAY 2005 - 2007

Provided overall architectural guidance and technical leadership to GE and HSBC accounts.

SOFTWARE MANAGER, MANHATTAN ASSOCIATES, Bengaluru, India, 2004 – 2005

• Managed the development of Distributed Order Management System (DOMS)

SENIOR CONSULTANT, TOTAL BUSINESS RESOURCES, USA, 1998-2004

• Developed software in Travel, Finance and Logistics domains.

SYSTEMS ANALYST, DATASOFT TECHNOLOGES, USA, 1997-1998

• Maintained and enhanced System 2000 (A wholesale distribution package).

ASSISTANT SYSTEMS ANALYST, TATA CONSULTANCY SERVICES, 1993-1996

• Developed software for customers: J. P. Morgan; Tata Steel; Rail Coach Factory, Kapurthala

Phone: 612-568-2426 CHANDRA PRAKASH 2 of 2 Email: cprakash@acm.org